(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T22:25:20.420248",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ないない
Nainai
ないじゃない
It's just not there, is it?
曖昧な愛 色のない愛
Ambiguous love, colorless love,
期待以外 他人事みたい
except for expectations, like someone else's affair.
お陰様 どちら様 応え様々
Thanks to you, who are you? Answers vary.
何者でもないまま
Remaining as a nobody,
何にもできないまま
unable to do anything,
生きるの無駄ですか？
is it useless to live?
悪いことですか？
Is it a bad thing?
ここにいない いない いないのは
The one who isn't here, isn't here, isn't here...
自分 自分
is myself, myself.
誰もいない いない いないまま
With nobody here, nobody here, nobody here,
掃き捨ててさよなら
swept away and saying goodbye,
嬉しくない 悲しくもない
I'm not happy, nor am I sad,
透明な気分
a transparent feeling.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
My lacking self, not even a face to face the world.
ない ない
Not there, not there.
笑えないじゃない
I can't even laugh, can I?
灰じゃない 愛 閉じたままかい
Not ashes, is love kept shut away?
返事はい 期待だけ大
Answering "yes", expectations are high,
いやいや 投げられたサイ
reluctantly, the die is cast,
目目は知らんない
what number it rolled, I don't know.
ここに居たい 居たい 居たいのも
The one who wants to stay, stay, stay here...
自分 自分
is myself, myself.
味わい 苦い 苦い 苦いまま
The taste remains bitter, bitter, bitter,
当てもなくさよなら
saying goodbye aimlessly.
帰らない 行く先もない
Not returning, having nowhere to go,
迷子な気分
feeling like a lost child.
間違えてない まだわからない
Made no mistake, but I still don't know.
ない ない
Not there, not there.
どうだっていいじゃない
Doesn't matter anyway, does it?
影も
Shadows,
形も
and shapes too,
いっそ無くしてしまえばいい
I might as well just lose them completely.
また灰 ひとつ ひとつから
Starting again, one by one, from the ashes,
始めればいい
it's fine if I start over.
ここに居ない 居ない 居ないのは 自分 自分
The one who isn't here, isn't here, isn't here is myself, myself.
誰も見ない 見ない 見ないまま 掃き捨ててさようなら
With nobody watching, watching, watching, sweep me away and say goodbye.
嬉しくない 悲しくもない 透明な気分
I'm not happy, nor am I sad, a transparent feeling.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
An incomplete self, ashamed to even show my face.
ない ない ないままで
Still missing, missing, missing,
ここに居たい 居たい 居たい
I want to be here, be here, be here,
笑いたいじゃない
Don't I want to smile?
せーの！
One, two!
でもそんなんじゃ だめ
But that won't do,
もうそんなんじゃ ほら
see, that really won't do.
心は進化するよ
My heart will keep evolving,
もっと もっと
more and more!
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If putting it into words would destroy our bond,
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
I thought I should just erase the words,
恐れてた
I was afraid.
だけどあれ？ なんか違うかも
But wait? Maybe something's different...
千里の道も一歩から
A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step.
石のようにかたいそんな意志で
With a determination as firm as stone,
塵も積もれば大和撫子？
if dust gathers, will it become a traditional maiden?
「し」抜きで いや死ぬ気で！
Without giving up—no, with my life on the line!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy-fluff, floating lightly,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
when you call my name, just that makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating lightly, fluffy-fluff,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
when you smile, just that brings a smile to my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
getting to meet you
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
でもそんなんじゃ だめ
But that won't do,
もうそんなんじゃ ほら
see, that really won't do.
心は進化するよ
My heart will keep evolving,
もっと もっと
more and more!
そうそんなんじゃ いやだ
No, I don't want it that way,
ねえそんなんじゃ まだ
hey, it's not enough yet.
私のこと見ててね
Keep watching me,
ずっと ずっと
forever and ever!
私の中のあなたほど
Compared to how much you mean to me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
my presence inside you
まだまだ大きくないことも
isn't that big yet,
分かってるけれど
I know that, but...
今この同じ瞬間
Right now in this same moment,
共有してる実感
the real feeling of sharing this time,
塵も積もれば大和撫子
a pile of dust becomes a Japanese maiden,
略して塵積も大和撫子！
or in short: Dust-piled Maiden!
くらくらり くらくらる
Dizzy-dizzy, spinning round,
あなたを見上げたら それだけで眩しすぎて
when I look up at you, you're just so dazzling.
くらくらる くらくらり
Spinning round, dizzy-dizzy,
あなたを想っている それだけで溶けてしまう
just thinking of you makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
getting to meet you
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
コイスル キセツハ
The season of falling in love
ヨクバリ サーキュレーション
is a greedy circulation.
コイスル キモチハ
The feeling of falling in love
ヨクバリ サーキュレーション
is a greedy circulation.
コイスル ヒトミハ
The eyes in love
ヨクバリ サーキュレーション
are a greedy circulation.
コイスル オトメハ
The maiden in love
ヨクバリ サーキュレーション
is a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy-fluff, floating lightly,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
when you call my name, just that makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating lightly, fluffy-fluff,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
when you smile, just that brings a smile to my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが...
getting to meet you...
めぐり逢えたことが
I'm so glad that we were able to meet,
幸せなの
I feel so happy.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good.
もうそんなんじゃほら
See, that just won't do.
心は進化するよ
My heart keeps on evolving,
もっともっと
more and more.
そうそんなんじゃいやだ
No, I don't want it that way.
ねぇそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's still not enough.
私のこと見ててね
Keep your eyes on me,
ずっとずっと
forever and ever.
あー！ノエル恋愛対象外でした！
Ah! Noel was excluded as a romantic interest!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
どうしても伝えたくて...
I really wanted to tell you...
ありがとう！お誕生日おめでとう！
Thank you! Happy birthday!
そうなんよ、1600歳になっちゃったよ。
That's right, I turned 1,600 years old!
1600歳... 永遠の1600歳ってこと？
1,600 years old... You mean eternally 1,600 years old?
いや、それ以上もそれ以下も年取らないから。
Well, I don't age above or below that anymore.
なるほどな。永久的な存在。
I see. An eternal existence.
ノエル、誕生日だからお願いがあるんだけど...
Noel, since it's my birthday, I have a favor to ask...
お願いって... 聞いてくれる？
Will you listen to my request?
一言だけ言っとくけど、大胸筋はあげられないからね。
Just so you know, I can't give you my pectoral muscles, okay?
うるさいよ！いらないよ！魔法で隠してるんだからいいの！
Shut up! I don't need them! I'm hiding mine with magic, so it's fine!
ちょっとさ... お願い事なんだけど、ママになってほしいんだけど...
So about my request... I want you to be my mama...
ママ？あら、どうしたの？
Mama? Oh, what happened?
最近ほら、去年とかさ、いっぱいお仕事あってちょっと疲れちゃってさ...
Well, recently and last year, I had so much work and got a bit tired...
めっちゃ頑張ってたもんね。
You've been working really hard.
膝枕とかしてほしくて...
So I want you to give me a lap pillow...
わかった。じゃあ、団長の膝においで。
Okay. Then come sit on Danchou's lap.
やったー！いいの？本当いいの？
Yay! Is it really okay?
いいよ。
It's okay.
お邪魔します。よいしょ。
Excuse me then. Ups-a-daisy.
あー可愛いねー。
Aww, so cute~
ノエルママ〜
Noel mama~
いつも頑張って偉いね〜
You're so good for working hard all the time~
ありがとう... ああ、癒やされる〜
Thank you... Ah, this is so comforting~
なでなでして...
Pat my head...
生きてるだけで偉いよ〜 よしよし...
You're great just for being alive~ There, there...
やべっ... みんな見てた！
Oh crap... Everyone was watching!
ライブだったか...
Ah, this was a live stream...
今日のことは忘れてください！すみません！
Please forget what happened today! I'm sorry!
せっかくだからさ、記念撮影しない？
Since we're here, why don't we take a photo?
そうだね、みんな見てるしね。
Good idea, since everyone's watching.
そうそう！一緒に写真撮ろう！
Yeah yeah! Let's take a photo together!
何を撮るんだい？
What kind of pose shall we do?
こうやって、こうやって... ぎゅーって！
Like this, like this... a tight hug!
さっきの終わりのポーズだね。
That was our pose at the end of the song.
そう！
Yup!
上からカメラさん撮れますか？
Cameraman, can you take it from above?
ちっちゃくて可愛いね〜
You're so small and cute~
えへへ〜
Ehehe~
胸邪魔じゃね？
Aren't your breasts in the way?
邪魔じゃないよ！当たってないでしょ！
They're not in the way! They're not hitting you, right?!
危ないよ！
It's dangerous!
次さ、ぶりっ子しない？
Next, why don't we pose cutely?
ぶりっ子！
Play cute!
「恋愛サーキュレーション」歌ったし、可愛さアピールしてくか！
Since we sang "Renai Circulation", let's show off our cuteness!
うん！
Yeah!
ぶりっ子、ぶりっ子... ぶりぶり〜
Play cute, play cute... super cute~
どう？
How is it?
可愛く撮って！可愛く！
Take cute pictures! Cutely!
ウインクとかもしちゃうかな？
Maybe I'll do a wink too?
ウインク！
Wink!
最後にさ、後ろにバックのイラスト流れたの分かる？覚えてる？
Lastly, do you remember the illustration shown in the background?
分かる！覚えてる覚えてる！
I know! I remember, I remember!
それでさ、そのポーズしたいんだけど...
I want to do that same pose...
いいね、いいね！
Sounds good!
出せるかな、スタジオの...
Can the studio staff bring it up...?
あ、出た！これ、やすゆきママが書いてくれてね...
Ah, there it is! Yasuyuki-mama drew this for us...
めっちゃ上手い！
It's so amazing!
そうなの！
I know, right!
このポーズしよう！可愛いでしょ！
Let's do this pose! Isn't it cute?
フリー素材です！後でTwitterとか載せてあげてください！
This is free material! Please post it on Twitter later!
いっぱい撮ってね！
Take lots of photos!
カメラさん、アップとかできますか？
Cameraman, can you zoom in?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おー！可愛い！
Ooh! So cute!
霊媒師とメイドさん。
A necromancer and a maid.
ね！メイドさんなんだよね！
Yeah! They're maids!
わたし満足しちゃったから...
I'm so satisfied now...
もうこのまま...
Now I just want to...
ノエルのママの膝の上で...
...stay right here on Noel mama's lap...
おねねする？
Are you going to sleep?
うん、ちょっと休む... 休憩します。
Yeah, resting a bit... Taking a break.
いっぱい休んで。よしよし...
Get lots of rest. There, there...
ノエルママ〜
Noel mama~
よしよし、おやすみだよ〜
There, there, good night~
ちょっと寝るね、おやすみ...
I'm gonna sleep a bit, good night...
雨とカプチーノ
Rain and Cappuccino
灰色に白んだ
The words faded to gray
言葉はカプチーノみたいな色してる
are the color of a cappuccino.
言い訳はいいよ 窓辺に置いてきて
I don't need excuses, just leave them by the window.
数え切れないよ
I can't keep count anymore.
灰色に白んだ
My heart, faded to gray,
心はカプチーノみたいな色してる
is the color of a cappuccino.
言い訳はいいよ
I don't need excuses,
煽ろうカプチーノ
let's drink up our cappuccino,
戯けた振る舞いして
and pretend to act foolish.
さぁ 揺蕩うように雨流れ
Now, as the rain flows swaying,
僕らに荒らす花に溺れ
drowning us in a storm of flowers,
君が褪せないような思い出を
so that memories of you will never fade,
どうか
please,
君が溢れないように
don't let yourself overflow.
波待つ海岸
On the shore waiting for waves,
紅夕差す日
as the crimson sunset shines,
窓に反射して
reflecting in the window,
八月 ヴィスビー 潮騒
August in Visby, the roar of the tide,
待ちぼうけ 海風一つで
left waiting in a single sea breeze.
夏泳いだ花の白さ 宵の雨
The white flowers we swam through in summer, the evening rain,
流れる夜に溺れ
drowning in the flowing night,
誰も褪せないような花一つ
a single flower so no one ever fades away,
どうか
please,
胸の内側に挿して
plant it inside my heart.
ずっとおかしいんだ
Something's been wrong for so long,
生き方一つ教えてほしいだけ
I just want you to teach me a way to live.
払えるものなんて僕にはもうないけど
Though I have nothing left to give in return,
何にも答えられないなら
if you can't answer anything,
言葉一つでもいいよ
even just a single word is enough.
わからないよ
I don't know,
本当にわかんないんだよ
I really just don't know.
さぁ 揺蕩うように雨流れ
Now, as the rain flows swaying,
僕らに荒らす花に溺れ
drowning us in a storm of flowers,
君が褪せないように書く詩を
I write this song so you'll never fade away,
どうか
please,
今も忘れないように
so that even now, I won't forget.
また一つ夏が終わって
As another summer comes to an end,
花一つを胸に抱いて
holding a single flower to my chest,
流れる瞼の裏で
behind my flowing eyelids,
君が褪せないようにこの詩を
I sing this song so you'll never fade away,
どうか
please,
君が溢れないように
don't let yourself overflow.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
『雨とカプチーノ』でした！
That was "Rain and Cappuccino"!
うわー！楽しかったー！
Wow, that was so much fun!
やっぱヨルシカさんめちゃくちゃいいね！
Yorushika's songs really are amazing!
いや、ルシアの歌さ、やっぱ合ってんなって思ったんだよねー。
Yeah, I thought Rushia's song choice really hit the mark!
いやいやいや、これさ、提案してくれたのってふーたんなんだよね。
No, no, no! The one who actually proposed it was you, Fuutan!
最初はね、ヨルシカさん絶対ルシアと一緒に歌いたいって思ってたから、歌えてよかった！
Initially, I really wanted to sing a Yorushika song together with Rushia, so I'm so glad we could!
いや本当にありがとう！なんかね、ルシアがヨルシカさん好きなの分かってくれてて…
Really, thank you so much! You knew how much Rushia loves Yorushika...
ふーたんも好きなんだよね、確か。
...and Fuutan likes them too, right?
そう！でもね、今回初めて歌ったんだよ、ヨルシカさん。結局選んでくれたじゃない？
Yeah! But you know, this was my first time singing Yorushika. You were the one who ended up choosing it, right?
そうなの。私がヨルシカさん歌いたいと思ってて、色々候補を出したしルシアからも出してくれてて、結局選んだこの「雨とカプチーノ」…
That's right! I wanted to sing Yorushika, so we both came up with suggestions, and in the end, we chose "Rain with Cappuccino"...
それをさ、ルシアがさ、決めてくれたのって、結局何がきっかけだったの？
So what made you finally decide on that song, Rushia?
あのね、すっごく迷ったの。
Well, you see... I was really torn!
迷ったんだけど、この「雨とカプチーノ」ってさ、すごく切ないじゃん？
I hesitated, but "Rain with Cappuccino" is just so bittersweet, right?
こう、なんていうのかな、心もしゅんってなるような、でも温かくなるような、なんていうのかな…
How should I put it... It makes your heart ache a bit, but also warms you up...
すごく難しいんだけど、それをふーたんと歌いたいなって、こうもうインスピレーションで思ったの！
It's hard to explain, but I felt this pure inspiration that I just HAD to sing it with Fuutan!
絶対似合うなって思ったんだよね！ / えー！嬉しい！
I knew it would suit us so well! / Aww, I'm so happy!
なんか2人デスやっぱさ、合うのがいいじゃん。どっちかだけじゃなくて、エモさみたいなのを入れたくてね。
Because it's best when a song fits both of us, right? Not just one person, but creating that emotional vibe together.
真面目に話しちゃった！ハハハ！
Ah, I ended up talking so seriously! Hahaha!
いつもは「ウギャー！」って言ってるのに！今日はなんか清楚らしくて可愛いんじゃない？
Even though you're usually going "Ugyaa!", today you seem so neat and cute, don't you?
ちょっと！ちょっと照れちゃうじゃん、ふーたん！
Hey! You're making me blush, Fuutan!
いいんだよ、「ウギャー！」って言っても！ / いやだよー！
It's fine even if you go "Ugyaa!" / No way!
今日はアイドルだからね！誕生日だしね！ / そうだよ！
Today I'm an idol! And it's my birthday! / That's right!
じゃあさ、アイドルっぽいさ、撮影とか一緒に写真撮る？
Then should we take some photo-worthy, idol-like poses together?
え、しようしよう！せっかくだからしよう！ポーズしよう！
Oh, let's do it, let's do it! Since we're here, let's pose!
よしよし。どうする？ / これにしよう！ / これね！
Alright, alright. What pose should we do? / Let me do this one! / This one, right!
みんな撮って撮って！ / 上からとか横からとか！ / いいねいいね！可愛いねー！
Everyone, take screenshot after screenshot! / From above, from the side! / Nice, nice! So cute!
自分で言うのもなんだけど可愛いね！ / あとハート作ろうか！
I know I'm saying it myself, but we're cute! / Next, let's make a heart!
難しいよ、ハート！ / あ、できたできた！
Making a heart is tough! / Ah, we did it, we did it!
出来た出来た！可愛い可愛い！ / 出来てる！可愛い！
We made it! So cute, so cute! / It turned out great! So cute!
めっちゃ上手く歌えた、ふーたんと！やったねー！
We sang so well together, Fuutan! We did it!
ちょっと休んじゃお！ / 休むな！
Let me take a quick break! / Don't take a break!
おいおいおい、まだ終わってないでしょ！立って！ / 立てなーい！助けてー！
Hey, hey, hey! It's not over yet, you know! Stand up! / I can't stand! Help me!
次のステージに行って貰うからね！ / がんばるー！
We're taking you to the next stage! / I'll do my best!
チューリングラブ / Music: ナユタ セイジ
[Title: Turing Love / Music: Nayuta Seiji]
あー、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love!
まずスキって基準もわからない
First off, I don't even know the standards for "liking."
要は、恋してるときが恋らしい
In short, being in love is what love is about.
客観？ 主観？ エビデンスプリーズ！
Objective? Subjective? Evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved with calculations!
まず普通の計算も解けない
First off, I can't even solve regular math!
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that kind of state is adorable.
もう大抵的事象において Q があって A を出して解けるのに
Most phenomena have a Q and yield an A to be solved,
勘違いして間違って 解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
So what is this feeling with no solution, full of mistakes?
DAZING!! モーションは相対性にステイ
DAZING!! Motion stays relative!
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, a mellow feeling unsolved even when staring into each other's eyes.
ワットイズラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What is love? Shall we prove it right now on 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
A question brought to life with words...
ハートで高鳴るアンサー
An answer throbbing in the heart...
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらの BPM
Even if measured, our BPM remains uncertain!
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love, I wouldn't believe it even if floating in space,
フォーリンラブ いまは ABC すらバグりそうだ
Falling love, right now even ABC seems glitched out!
なんでか教えてオイラー
Tell me why, Euler!
感想きかせてフェルマー
Let me hear your thoughts, Fermat!
予測不可能性 いま触れてみる
Unpredictability—let me touch it now!
さあ証明しよう 間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it so there are no mistakes!
証明しよう この感情全部全部
Let's prove every single one of these feelings!
証明しよう 正解があるなら
Let's prove it if a correct answer exists!
証明しよう シンプルな Q.E.D.
Let's prove it, a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい！
Today of all days, I want to prove it!
目に見えない 無理難題を
An invisible, impossible problem...
ASAP!
あー、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love.
まずスキって基準もわからない
First of all, I don't even know the standards for "like".
要は、恋してるときが恋らしい
In short, it seems love is when you're in love.
客観？ 主観？ エビデンスプリーズ！
Objective? Subjective? Evidence please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved through calculation.
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, I can't even solve basic math.
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
In short, such a state is cute.
もう大抵の事象において Q があって A を出して解けるのに
In most cases, there's a Q, and you produce an A to solve it, yet...
勘違いって間違って 解のないこの気持ちなんだろう (検証 is 不明瞭)
What is this feeling without a solution, mistaken and misunderstood? (Verification is unclear)
DAZING!! モーションは相対性にステイ
DAZING!! Motion stays relative!
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love — a mellow feeling unsolvable even if we stare at each other.
ワットイズラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What is love? Shall we prove it right now with 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出すクエッション
A question brought forth with words...
(クエッション！)
(Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー
An answer throbbing in the heart...
(アンサー！)
(Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらの BPM
Measured with uncertainty, our BPM.
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love — even if we float in the air, I won't believe it, but...
フォーリンラブ いまは ABC すらバグりそうだ
Falling in love — right now, even ABC seems to be bugging out.
なんですか教えよオイラー
Tell me somehow, Euler!
(オイラー！)
(Euler!)
感想きかせてフェルマー
Let me hear your thoughts, Fermat!
(フェルマー！)
(Fermat!)
予測不可能性 いま触れてみる
Unpredictability — let's touch it now.
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it (let's prove it) so there are no mistakes.
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove it (let's prove it), all these feelings, every bit of them.
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let's prove it (let's prove it), if there's a correct answer.
証明しよう (証明しよう) シンプルな Q.E.D.
Let's prove it (let's prove it), a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい！(しよう！)
Today of all days, I want to prove it! (Let's do it!)
目に見えない 無理難題を
This invisible, impossible challenge...
ASAP!
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love — even if we float in the air, I won't believe it, but...
フォーリンラブ いまは XYZ すら分かりそうだ
Falling in love — right now, I feel like I could even understand XYZ.
確かめてピタゴラス
Confirm it, Pythagoras!
(ピタゴラス！)
(Pythagoras!)
確信させてよリーマン
Make me certain, Riemann!
(リーマン！)
(Riemann!)
予測変異性 いま触れてみる
Predicted variability — let me touch it now.
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Come on, let me prove it (let's prove it) so there are no mistakes.
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove it (let's prove it), all these feelings, every bit of them.
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let me prove it (let's prove it), if there's a correct answer.
証明しよう (証明しよう) シンプルな Q.E.D.
Let's prove it (let's prove it), a simple Q.E.D.
るしあ、おめでとう！
Rushia, happy birthday!
マリン！チューリングラブどうだった？
Marine! How was "Turing Love"?
いやー、幸せでしたね。なんか二人でこんなイチャイチャと踊っちゃったりなんかして。
Ah, I was so happy! We got to dance together all lovey-dovey like that.
楽しかったね。ちょっとイチャイチャしちゃったね。
It was fun. We got a bit clingy, didn't we?
しちゃったねー。
We sure did!
ねー。楽しかった。いつもね、別の曲だったけど、初めて歌ったからね。
Right? It was fun. We usually sing a different song, but this was our first time singing this together!
ね！新鮮だった！
Yeah! It felt so fresh!
ねー。ダンスもね、めちゃめちゃ可愛くて、大変で...でも楽しかった！思い出になった、思い出に。
Yeah. The dance was super cute and intense... but it was fun! It became a great memory.
思い出になった！ダンス頑張ったね！
A great memory! You really worked hard on the dance!
ね、頑張った頑張った！
Yeah, we both worked really hard!
ね、キレッキレ。
Yeah, super sharp movements.
ねー、ねー、ねー...
Hey, hey, hey...
何ですか？
What is it?
なんか、冷たくない？
Aren't you being a bit cold?
え？何急に？
Huh? What all of a sudden?
なんかさ...もっと温かくしてよー！
Well... show me some more warmth!
はいはい？
Yes, yes?
えー？あったかく...じゃあちょっと抱き締めちゃうかな！
Eh? Warmth... then maybe I'll give you a hug!
あ、よしよし... / 近い近い！さっき...近いの、近いよ！
Ah, there, there... / Too close, too close! Earlier... you're way too close!
あれ？さっきまで...近付いてバックじゃん！
Huh? Up until now... you were stepping back!
えー？なんか近づいてたっていいでしょ！温かいでしょ！何が嫌なんだ言ってみろー！
Eh? It's fine if I get closer! It's warm, right? Tell me what you don't like about it!
離れてよちょっと！離れて！
Get off me for a sec! Get off!
あ、でもマリン、今のいいね。ちょっと今のさ、みんなに写真撮ってもらおう？
Ah, but Marine, that was good just now. Let's ask everyone to take a photo of that!
あ、確かに！ちょっと撮ってもらいましょうか。
Ah, true! Let's get them to take a photo.
はい、今撮ってもらってるからね。はい、皆さん！
Okay, they're taking photos now. Okay, everyone!
どうですかー？撮ってください。
How is this? Please take pictures.
どうですかー？
How is it?
クンクンか？るし... / 離れて！髪の毛...もうおしまい！おしまい！
Are you sniffing me? Rushi... / Get off! My hair... Okay, that's enough! It's over!
もう、つれないなー。 / おしまい！
Geez, so cold... / It's over!
じゃあ、もう1ポーズくらい取ってもらえますか？ / なんか撮る？撮る？
Well then, can you take one more pose for us? / Should we do another?
やっぱちょっとチューリングラブさ、ほら踊ったからさ、チューリングラブのポーズしますか？
Since we danced to "Turing Love", should we do a "Turing Love" pose?
あ、いいね！よしよしよし！
Oh, that sounds good! Okay, okay, okay!
行くよー、じゃあ、おい！
Here we go, then, hey!
どうですか？
How is this?
はい、かわいいでしょー！
Yes, super cute, right?
撮ってねー。
Take photos, okay?
いいね。良くない？
Nice. Isn't it great?
かわいい、いいね。
Cute, nice.
ね、胸のサイズ差が際立っている...
See, the difference in chest size really stands out...
うるさーい！
Shut up!
ほんとにさー、そんなの脂肪じゃん！
Honestly, that's just fat anyway!
あーあ、いつものが始まりましたねー。
Ah-ah, here goes the usual routine again.
ま、そのいつもの話はね、いいとして...
Well, setting that usual talk aside...
いや、でもるしあさー...
No, but Rushia...
なんかあのさ、今嫌なこと思い出しちゃったな。
I just remembered something unpleasant.
え、何何？
Eh, what what?
船長のさ、100万人記念の時に一緒にさ、『ニャン生』歌ったじゃん。
During my 1 Million Subscribers stream, we sang "Nyansei" together, right?
あれさー、なんかおかゆ先輩とも歌ってたよね！
You sang that with Okayu-senpai too, didn't you!
いやおかゆ先輩マジかっこよかったなー！
Man, Okayu-senpai was seriously so cool!
もしかして、チューリングラブも...まさかおかゆ先輩と歌いたかったの！？
Don't tell me, "Turing Love" too... Did you actually want to sing it with Okayu-senpai?!
おかゆ先輩と歌いたかったな！今度歌おう、おかゆ先輩と！誘っちゃお！
I would've loved to sing with Okayu-senpai! Let's sing together next time! I'll invite her!
あーイライラする！イライラしてきた！
Ah, I'm getting so annoyed! So pissed off!
うわー！痛い！るしあ！お仕置きが必要のようだな！
Uwaah! Ouch! Rushia! Looks like you need a punishment!
おい！生意気言ってんじゃないよ！
Hey! Don't talk fresh to me!
うらぁ！おい！
Urah! Hey!
fancy baby doll
[Song: fancy baby doll]
チェックのキャミソールを着て
Wearing a plaid camisole,
今夜…ねえ！遊びに行くわ
tonight... hey! I'm going out to play.
スウィートな服は宝物
Sweet clothes are my treasure,
君は少し恥ずかしそうね
but you look a little embarrassed.
ハートのネイルのピンクは…
The pink on my heart-patterned nails is...
ホントはちょっと、大胆よ
actually a little daring.
12時過ぎのシンデレラ
A Cinderella past midnight,
もっと夢見せて
show me more of the dream,
もっとそばに来て
come closer to me,
tonight 二人きり let's party!
tonight, just the two of us, let's party!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛い子に生まれなかった
I wasn't born the cutest girl in the world.
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回言われてもまだ不安だわ
Even if you tell me tens of thousands of times, I'm still anxious.
あ・い・し・て・る？
Do... you... love... me?
カートにあふれてしまうほど
So much that it overflows from the shopping cart,
今日は…ねえ！お買い物の日
today is... hey! Shopping day!
スウィートな帽子と手袋
A sweet hat and gloves,
おしゃれするとキラキラするの
dressing up makes me sparkle.
大きなハートが欲しい
I want a big heart,
ホントはちょっと弱虫よ
truth is, I'm a bit of a coward.
シープのブーツ脱ぎ捨てて
Kicking off my sheepskin boots,
もっと愛される sweet girl 女の子
a sweet girl who wants to be loved more,
ねえ 目指したい from my heart
hey, that's what I aim for, from my heart.
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛いって今日も言ってね
Tell me I'm the cutest in the world today, too.
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回生まれても君に会いたい
No matter how many tens of thousands of times I'm born, I want to meet you.
本当よ
It's true.
ハートのネイルのピンクは…
The pink on my heart-patterned nails is...
ホントはもっと、大胆よ
actually much more daring.
12時過ぎのシンデレラ
A Cinderella past midnight,
もっと夢見せて
show me more of the dream,
もっとそばに来て
come closer to me,
tonight 二人きり let's party!
tonight, just the two of us, let's party!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛いって今日も言ってね
Tell me I'm the cutest in the world today, too.
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回生まれても君に会いたい
No matter how many tens of thousands of times I'm born, I want to meet you.
約束よ
It's a promise.
イエーイ！
Yay!
ぺこちゃん！
Peko-chan!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
最高なんだよね！
It was the best!
一緒に歌えて嬉しかったぺこだよ、fancy baby doll！
I was so happy we got to sing fancy baby doll together, peko!
ねー！可愛かったね、るしぇとぺこちゃんの
Right! It was so cute, Rushia and Peko-chan's...
ねー！fancy baby doll！
Yeah! "fancy baby doll"!
やっぱり、アイドルぺこなのかな？
Guess we really are idols, peko!
当たり前じゃん、るしぇとぺこちゃんだよ！
Of course we are! It's Rushia and Peko-chan!
なんかさ、たまにさ、芸人って言われてることあるけどさー
Like, sometimes people call us comedians, though...
うん
Yeah.
本当ぺこだよね！アイドルぺこなのだけどペコらたちも！
So true, peko! We really are idols too, peko!
マジで！失礼極まりないよね！
Seriously! That's super rude!
ほんとにすごいんだよ、もう
It's really amazing!
この衣装、近くで見たらもう一緒じゃない？
Look at this costume up close, isn't it almost identical?
いやもうこのファンシーめミイラも
I mean, even with this fancy mummy look,
animated まさにアイドルぺこらちゃんな、やっぱりぺこらちゃんな
she's totally idol Pekora-chan! As expected of Pekora-chan!
でしょ、ターンとか可愛かったでしょ、るしあたちの、バーンって回るやつ！
Right? The turns were cute too, right? The way we turned around with a bang!
連携ね！ね！
Great teamwork, right? Right!
そうなんだよね。でね、
That's right! And you know,
るしあたちさ、芸人とか言われるじゃん。
You know how people call us comedians and all?
まあね、言われることが多いぺこですがね。
Well, yeah, we do get called that a lot, peko.
でもアイドルじゃん！
But we're idols!
そうぺこなね。
That's true, peko.
だからこそさ、ちょっと今からさ、可愛いポーズ対決しない？
That's why, right now... why don't we have a cute pose battle?
突然！突然可愛いポーズ対決？
Out of nowhere?! A cute pose battle out of nowhere?
そう、アイドルらしい、どっちがなんか...
Yeah! A battle to see who...
アイドルの力が強いかっていうのを今決めるってことぺこ？
To decide right now which of us has stronger idol power, peko?
今対決するとかどう？
How about we battle right now?
いいよ、かかってきなさいぺこ！
Fine, bring it on, peko!
アイドルぺこですから！任せなさい！どんなポーズでもできますぺこですから！
I'm an idol, peko! Leave it to me! I can do any pose, peko!
どうする？一-一緒にやるの？「せーの」で、2人でやるの？それとも片方ずつ見せていく感じ？
How should we do it? Together? On "ready, set", both of us together? Or show them one by one?
一緒にやっぱり、みんなにも写真とか撮ってほしいから、一緒にパーッてやっていこうか。
Let's do them together! We want everyone to take screenshots, so let's do them simultaneously!
オッケーぺこ！
Okay, peko!
えっとさ、どうしよう、どうしよう、まず1個目...
Um, what should we do... for the first one...
可愛いポーズ...あれにしよう！
A cute pose... Yeah, let's go with that one!
ぺこらは決めました！
Pekora has decided!
早っ！
So fast!
決まりましたよ！
I'm ready!
決まった、オッケーオッケー、決まった。
Decided? Okay, okay, I'm ready too.
いくよ？シャッターよろしくね。いくよ？せーの...
Here we go! Get your camera shutters ready! Ready, set...
はい！
Pose!
あれ？なんか一緒...
Huh? Somehow we're...
あれ？なんで一緒なの？！
Huh?! Why are we doing the same thing?!
一緒になっちゃった！
We matched!
被ったんだけど！
We totally overlapped!
打ち合わせしてないのに！
Even though we didn't discuss it beforehand!
運命感じちゃうじゃない！
Doesn't this feel like destiny?!
打ち合わせしてないからね！
We really didn't plan this!
ね、すごいぺこらちゃん！びっくり！もう1個！もう1個決まってるぺこら？るしあ決まったんだけど。
Right?! That's amazing, Pekora-chan! What a surprise! One more! Pekora, do you have another one ready? I've decided.
もう1個ね！もう1個えっと...待って...
One more! One more, umm... wait...
あー、あれにしよう！
Ah! Let's go with that!
オッケー、決めた。これで被ったら怖いぺこな...
Okay, decided! It'd be scary if we match again, peko...
怖いよね！行くよ？
It would be scary, right! Ready?
せーの、はい！
Ready, set, pose!
あー！同じ！
Ah--! Same again!
また一緒！
Same again!
ちょっと待って！やばい！体幹が...！
Wait a sec! Oh no! Our core balance is...!
体幹がヤバい！体幹がブレブレだから！
Our core is weak! Our balance is all wobbly!
体幹がね！
The balance, right!
アイドル感が分かってぬ...
We lack idol composure...
きっつい...あ、ごめん...
Ow, that was rough... Ah, sorry...
アイドルたるもの片足立ち...
As idols, standing on one leg...
ずっと過ごしていかなきゃいけないぺこなのに、ぺこらたちきつかったよ、これちょっと...
we're supposed to be able to stay like this forever, peko, but that was tough for us...
そうね！ラストでいこう、ラストで！
True! Let's do a last one, last one!
ラストも最大級の可愛いあれにしようかなー！
For the last one, let's do the ultimate cute pose!
早っ！決まってんの？！
So fast! You already decided?!
えへっ！勝ったな！ね？
Ehe! I've won this time! Right?
威厳と慈悲があるぺこなの決めよ。勝ったわ！
I'll pick something with dignity and mercy, peko. I've won!
じゃあ超のぺこで行くよ！おいおい、行くよ！せーの！
Alright, going with super-Peko! Oi oi, here we go! Ready, set!
はい！あー！
Pose! Ah--!
前目で見せてんじゃないぺこだよ！
Don't step forward to block me, peko!
私の勝ちー！
I win!
ズルい！ズルいぞ、ちょっと！
Unfair! That's unfair!
これは2人とも優勝ぺこじゃない？お互いに可愛いな！
Isn't this a win for both of us, peko? We're both cute!
どっちかとか無く両方アイドルで可愛い！ってことで、この辺にしとくか、今日は！
Neither wins, both are cute idols! So let's leave it at that for today!
そうぺこなのね。ね！
That's right, peko. Right!
じゃあさ、ぺこらちゃん、次のさ、曲行きたいからさ、一緒ジャンプしない？
So, Pekora-chan, since we want to move on to the next song, why don't we jump together?
あ、よくあのジャンプしたら次のところにいるみたいな感じぺこ？
Ah, like when you jump, you appear in the next setup, peko?
そう！やろう、やろう！
Exactly! Let's do it, let's do it!
いくよ、ぺこらちゃん、今日ほんとにありがとね！こちらこそありがとぺこ！オッケー！
Here we go, Pekora-chan! Thank you so much for today! Thank you too, peko! Okay!
次の場所へ、せーの！
To the next place, ready, set...
はい！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Ha--i! Hello everyone!
どこから来たの？
Where did you guys come from?
ちょっとぺこらと飛んできたんだよね！飛んできたぺこだよ！
We just jumped over here with Pekora! We jumped over, peko!
飛んできた？そうだよー！
Jumped over? That's right!
ファンタジーだからね、起こることできちゃう。ファンタジーだからね。
Because we're Fantasy, we can make anything happen! Because we're Fantasy.
そう、今日はこの後ね、5人でとある曲を歌いたくて、やってまいりました！
Yes! Today after this, the 5 of us wanted to sing a certain song, so here we are!
なんだろう？集まってもらいました！
What could it be? I asked everyone to gather!
分かった！アレでしょ！『きらめきライダー☆』とかかな？ちょ、おいおいおい！
I got it! Is it that one? "Kirameki Rider☆" or something? Wait, hey, hey, hey!
あれ？あれ？5人の曲...分かる人ー！
Wait, wait, a song for the 5 of us... who knows it?!
あれ、嘘じゃん！
Wait, no way!
ねぇ、忘れないで絆を！間違えちゃったからなー！
Hey, don't forget our bond! Ah, I made a mistake!
これじゃないの？ 違うよ、ほら
Isn't it this one? No, look!
オータムとか… ねえ！
Autumn or something... Hey!
まぁ５人だからね
Well, since there's five of us...
イースターミュージックもね、歌ったことない
We've never sung Easter Music either...
歌った歌った！ほら！
We did, we did! Look!
い…あ！焼肉！
Y- Ah! Yakiniku!
焼肉！当たったよ焼肉！
Yakiniku! You got Yakiniku right!
ぺこら言っちゃって！
Pekora, say it!
言っちゃっていいぺこですか？正解言っちゃうよ？いい？
Can Pekora say it? I'm gonna say the right answer! Ready?
うん！
Yeah!
行くよ？ぺこらマジで言っちゃうよ？いいの？本当に？
Here I go, okay? Pekora is really gonna say it. Is that fine? Really?
分かるかな？
Will you get it?
待って、他に５人で歌った曲ってなんかあったっけな…
Wait, were there any other songs we five sang together...?
もう！
Jeez!
並ぶよ！いくよ、せーの！
Line up! Here we go, ready, set!
並ぶよ？
Line up?
うん！
Yeah!
並んでから！並んでからぺこ！並んでからな！
After we line up! After we line up, peko! Line up first!
うん！
Yeah!
行きます！
Here we go!
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ！
Interact Fantasia!
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ
[Title: Interact Fantasia]
わくわくは止まらないね いんたらくとふぁんたじあ
The excitement won't stop, Interact Fantasia!
Welcome Fantasia きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル Welcome Fantasia Yes!
Welcome Fantasia! This place is surely an everlasting fairytale. Welcome Fantasia, Yes!
ぺこら！段々と目指すは頂点だ ほらついてくるぺこ？
Pekora! Bit by bit, I'm aiming for the top. Hey, are you following me, peko?
るしあ！ちょっと待ってみんなで一緒にね なんか頼りなくない？
Rushia! Hold on a second, let me do it together with everyone. Doesn't that sound a bit unreliable?
フレア！怖いものなし進めいざ前進！
Flare! Fearing nothing, forge ahead!
ノエル！たまには泣いちゃうけど負けないよ！
Noel! I might cry once in a while, but I won't lose!
マリン！さあ手を取り合ったら 冒険の幕が開ける！
Marine! Now, when we take each other's hands, the curtain on our adventure rises!
立ち待ち過ぎて行く昨日の その目に焼き付け
Engrave in your eyes the yesterday that passed while standing and waiting.
広がる空も 海も大地も 重ね合った思い出を溢れさせて
The expanding sky, the sea, and the earth too, overflowing with memories we created together,
明日へと走り続けよう
Let's keep running toward tomorrow!
果てしない夢を追う まっすぐに 君となら怖くはないから
Chasing an endless dream straight ahead, because with you, I'm not afraid.
溜まったエモ全開 その背中に預け合い
Releasing all stored emotions, trusting in each other's backs,
みじかき道も 楽しみながら走れる
We can run through even short paths while enjoying ourselves.
心が今魔法をつげる
Our hearts cast magic right now.
さあ行くよ 進むべき未来が待ってる
Come on, let's go! The future we ought to advance toward is waiting!
他でもない君がいるから
Because you, and no one else, are here,
つなげよう 君と僕の世界 ここから旅は始まっている
Let's connect your world and mine, the journey begins right here!
Welcome Fantasia きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル Welcome Fantasia Yes!
Welcome Fantasia! This place is surely an everlasting fairytale. Welcome Fantasia, Yes!
手を振れ！手を伸ばして日常を照らし出すトゥインクルウェイ
Wave your hands! Reach out and light up everyday life on this twinkle way!
退屈にバイバイ 声あげスタート ついてきてくれるよね？
Say bye-bye to boredom, call out and start! You'll follow along, right?
１！今を照らす時が来た
One! The time to light up the present has come.
２！心の準備はオッケー？
Two! Is your heart ready?
３！さあ鐘を鳴らせば 伝説が第一歩拓く
Three! Now, ring the bell, and the first step of our legend will open up!
真っ直ぐに踏み出した勇気が 魔法になるから
Because the courage to step straight forward turns into magic!
世界の果ても 次元のかべも 吹き飛ばして 今君に会いにいこう
Blowing away the ends of the world and dimensional walls, let's go meet you right now!
一緒に飛び出してみない？
Won't you leap out together with us?
届かない夢はない どこへでも 君とならたどり着けるから
No dream is unreachable, anywhere at all, because with you, we can reach it.
束ねた声援を その両手に握りしめ
Clasping those gathered cheers in both hands,
白紙の地図を 描きまわして駆け出そう
Let's paint over this blank map and start running!
願いとともに歌う 聞こえるよ
Singing together with our wishes, I can hear it!
窓越しのファンタジーであっても
Even if it's a fantasy through a screen,
出会いは幻じゃないから
Our encounter is no illusion!
つなげよう 君と僕の声 奇跡を奏で合うシンフォニー
Let's connect your voice and mine, a symphony harmonizing miracles!
いつまでも
Forever and always!
もっと強くなりたくて
Wanting to become even stronger,
ずっと笑いあいたくて
Wanting to keep laughing together,
広がる気持ち強く結ぶ
Tightly tying together our expanding feelings.
君と出会えたよ 失敗も後悔もさせるわけないよ
I was able to meet you! There's no way I'll let us fail or have regrets!
だって毎日 楽しすぎるでしょ？
After all, every single day is way too fun, right?
ときめきの先の先へ
Beyond the very edge of excitement,
裸足で駆け抜けろ！
Run through barefoot!
行こう！果てしない夢を追う まっすぐに 君となら怖くはないから
Let's go! Chasing an endless dream straight ahead, because with you, I'm not afraid.
怖くはないから
...because I'm not afraid,
戸惑いも全部
Even all our hesitation,
その背中に預け合い
we entrust to each other's backs.
道なき道も
Even on paths untrodden,
楽しみながら走れる
we can run while enjoying the journey.
心が今を告げる
Our hearts announce the present.
さあ行くよ
Come on, let's go!
進むべき未来が待ってる
The future we must head toward is waiting.
他でもない君がいるから
Because it's none other than you who is here,
繋げよう 君と僕の世界
let's connect your world and mine.
いつまでも
Forever and ever,
旅は終わらない
our journey will never end.
Welcome fantasy Let's go yeah!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
みんな完璧だったね！
Everyone was perfect!
当たり前ぺこだよ！
Of course we were, peko!
ライブ以来ぺこだもんね！
It's been since our live concert, peko!
ねー、楽しかった！また歌える時が来るとは思わなかった！
Yeah, that was so fun! I never thought we'd get to sing it again!
ところでね、みんな、今年も入ったけど...
By the way, everyone, now that the new year has started...
2022年...
2022...
みんなのさ、目標聞いてもいいかな？
Can I ask what everyone's goals are?
目標？
Goals?
抱負でもいいよ！
A resolution is fine too!
みんなの？それとも自分の？
Everyone's, or our individual ones?
みんなの！先にるしあから言おうかな？
Everyone's! Should Rushia go first?
あ、いいよ！
Ah, sure!
はい！潤羽るしあ！
Okay! I'm Uruha Rushia!
3期生みんなと地上波に出たいです！
I want to appear on terrestrial TV with all of 3rd Gen!
おおー！
Ooh!
でっかく出ました！
I went big with that!
5人で出てないぺこだと思う！
I don't think all five of us have appeared together yet, peko!
うん、そうなんだ！出たいなー！
Yeah, that's right! I want to appear!
じゃ、次ね、ノエル！
Okay, next up is Noel!
はい！団長は...
Yes! As for the Captain...
3期生みんなでお揃いのものとかをちょっと付けたりとか...
I'd like for all of 3rd Gen to wear matching items or something...
あ、いいねー！
Ah, that's nice!
女の子だね！可愛いね！
So girlish! That's cute!
お揃いにしたい！素敵だよね！
I want to get matching things! That's so lovely!
お揃いとかくれるもんね、お土産とか！
She gives us matching gifts and souvenirs after all!
これ水色だからペコラだ、とかね！
Like, "This is light blue so it's Pekora," and so on!
可愛いよね！ありがとうね、いつも！
How cute! Thank you as always!
まだぬいぐるみ大事にしてるんで！
I'm still taking good care of the plushie!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
じゃ、次、ぺこちゃん！
Okay, next up, Peko-chan!
はい！ぺこらは...
Yes! As for Pekora...
大人の人たちの協力がないとできないのかも知れないぺこですけど...
This might not be possible without help from adults, peko, but...
お？何々？
Ooh? What is it?
ホロライブファンタジー3期生のギャルゲーを誰か作ってください！
Could someone please make a gal game for Hololive Fantasy 3rd Gen!
ギャルゲー！？
A gal game!?
意外だねー！めちゃくちゃいいじゃん！
That's surprising! That sounds awesome!
3期生でのゲームとかそういうの...
A game with 3rd Gen or something like that...
そういうのとか何か欲しいなって、今年は思ったぺこかな！
I thought this year that I'd really like something like that, peko!
やりたくない？カバーで作る方が早いかもだけどね！
Wouldn't you want that? It might be faster if Cover made it though!
攻略したい！めっちゃいいじゃん！
I want to romance everyone! That's so good!
じゃあちょっと、ゲームもお願いします！
Well then, please make a game for us too!
お願いしますー！
Please!
じゃ、次、マリン！
Okay, next up, Marine!
地上波っていうのが出たから、地上波は地上波でも、アニメにしましょう！
Since "terrestrial TV" came up, even if it's terrestrial TV, let me say an anime!
アニメー！？いいねー！
An anime!? That's great!
地上波のテレビに出たらどうせ滑り散らかすんで...
If we appear on terrestrial TV, we'd end up completely flopping anyway...
やめてー！
Stop it!
アニメの中に行きましょう！アニメ化したい！
Let's go inside an anime! I want an anime adaptation!
練習しなきゃ！演技頑張らなきゃね！
We gotta practice! We gotta do our best with acting!
じゃ、次、フレア！
Okay, next up, Flare!
やっぱり地上波は出たいなって思うんだけど...
I also want to appear on terrestrial TV, but...
私たちに一番合ってるのって、そうだなぁ...
The one that suits us best, let me see...
M-1とか？
M-1 Grand Prix or something?
お前一人で出ろよ！
Enter by yourself!
みんなで一緒に出ようよー！
Let's enter together with everyone!
嫌だー！
No way!
誰がネタ披露すんだよ！
Who's gonna perform the comedy routine?!
ま、みんなで色んなジャンル出たいねってことで！
Well, basically we all want to appear in various genres!
みんなで一致してるのは、テレビとかゲームとかだったね！
What we all agreed on was TV, games, and things like that!
やりたいね！今年叶えよう！叶えるぞー！
We really want to do it! Let's make it come true this year! We're gonna do it!
やるぞー！よろしくお願いしますー！
We're gonna do it! Thank you for your support!
じゃあさ、みんなでスクショ...
Well then, let's take a screenshot together...
あ、いいね！
Oh, nice!
揃った？揃った？
Are we all aligned?
写真だ！写真、よしよしよし、揃って
A photo! A photo! Okay, okay, line up.
どんなのがいい？
What kind of pose should we do?
ちょっとみんなでこう...あ、縮こまるか
Wait, let's all... Ah, crouch down?
るーちゃん真ん中に！るーちゃん真ん中に！
Put Ru-chan in the middle! Ru-chan in the middle!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
邪魔なんですけど！
Hey, you're blocking me!
見えないんだけど！
I can't see!
こんな感じでいいか？
Is a pose like this okay?
マリンが隠れちゃってる！
Marine is completely hidden!
イェーイ！
Yay!
これさ、お客さんの方、反対側向いても撮りたくない？
Hey, don't you want to take one facing the audience?
あ、いいね！回るのね！
Oh, nice! We turn around, right?
よくライブでやるやつ！
The thing they often do at live shows!
あ、エモい！すごい！
Oh, so emotional! Amazing!
しゃがんでね
Crouch down, okay?
るしあ、ぶりっ子してるわ
Rushia is playing cute!
私、ぶりっ子ってどうしたらいいの？
What should I do to play cute?
かがんだ方がいいかな？
Is it better to crouch lower?
こうか？こうか？
Like this? Like this?
いいね！
Nice!
たくさん撮って！
Take lots of photos!
カメラもっと上から！
Camera, from further up!
あ、いいね！
Oh, nice!
ここにサイン入れたいね、みんなの
I want to put everyone's signature right here.
取れた？取れた？
Did you get it? Took it?
可愛い！
So cute!
時間も迫ってきたんで、みんな...
Time is running short, so everyone...
今日は、ありがとう本当に！
Thank you so much for today!
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
今年もどうかみんなで仲良く過ごしましょう
Let me hope we can all get along and spend a great year together.
じゃあみんな、また明日もー！
Well then everyone, see you again tomorrow!
オッケー！おやすみー！
Okay! Good night!
私はいつも臆病者で 何をするにも怖くて
I was always a coward, afraid of doing anything,
すぐ諦めちゃうんだ
and I would give up right away.
自信だって全然なくて 人の背中ばかり見ていた
With no confidence at all, I only looked at the backs of others.
それでいいと思ってた だけど振り返った
I thought that was fine, but when you turned around
あなたが笑ってくれたこと
and smiled at me...
何を話したのかも覚えていないけれど
I don't even remember what we talked about, but
散らばる言葉は春の匂いがした
the scattered words smelled of spring.
色が恋なんだって 初めて気づいたんだよ
I realized for the first time that this is love.
出会えたことが 話せたことが こんなに嬉しくて
Being able to meet you, to talk with you, makes me so happy.
確かめたいんだ 溢れ出すこの思いを
I want to confirm these overflowing feelings.
もっと近くで伝えられたらいいのに
I wish I could convey them to you from up close,
だけど今の私ではダメなんだ
but as I am right now, it's no good.
私はいつでも不器用で 上手く言葉が出なくて
I'm always awkward, unable to express my words properly,
思っていることが綺麗に伝わればいいのに
wishing my thoughts could be conveyed clearly.
あなたの事ばかり見ていた 偶然を期待しては
I looked only at you, hoping for a coincidence,
もしかしたらなんて思い描いたりして
imagining "what if" scenarios...
だけどふとした時に 思いがけず気づいたんだ
But in a sudden moment, I unexpectedly realized
あなたの視線の先にいる人のこと
about the person standing at the end of your gaze.
こんなに痛いんだって 初めて思い知るんだ
I realize for the first time how much this hurts.
今のままでも幸せだって 思ってたはずなのに
Even though I was supposed to be happy as things were,
独り言のような思いは涙に変わり
these monologue-like thoughts turn into tears,
心配なんてしてほしいわけじゃないのに
and though I don't mean to make you worry...
でもね やっぱり少しだけ
Yet, after all, just a little bit...
されたいな
I want you to care.
弱気になると どうせ私なんかだって いつも諦めてたけど
When I feel discouraged, thinking "someone like me anyway", I always gave up, but...
痛くても
Even if it hurts,
辛くても
even if it's painful,
私が見つけた 私だけの
this feeling that is mine alone,
この気持ちは
which I found,
放したくないよ
I don't want to let it go.
これが恋なんだって
That this is what love is,
初めて気づいたんだよ
I realized for the very first time.
風に揺られて どこを向いても
Swaying in the wind, no matter where I turn,
あなたへ伸びてゆくんだ
I keep reaching out to you.
誰よりもきっと あなたのことが好きだよ
More than anyone else, I surely love you.
もっと近くで この気持ち伝えたいの
I want to convey these feelings to you from closer by.
だから こんな私では
So... for someone like me,
ダメですか？
am I not good enough?
みんなー！
Everyone!
お誕生日配信見てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for watching my birthday stream!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
るしあは今日本当に素敵な1日になれたよ！
Rushia had a truly wonderful day today!
お誕生日配信見に来てくれて本当に本当にありがとう！
Thank you so so much for coming to watch my birthday stream!
そして！
And...
お誕生日記念として販売するグッズの案内をするね！
I'd like to introduce the merchandise available for my birthday celebration!
それではまず、1点目はこちら！
So first, here is item number one!
やすゆき先生描き下ろしの花嫁るしあアクリルスタンド！
A Bride Rushia acrylic stand with new illustration by Yasuyuki-sensei!
見て見て！
Look, look!
すっごく可愛くない？
Isn't it super cute?
めちゃくちゃ綺麗じゃない？
Isn't it so pretty?
もうこれはね、るしあみんなのお嫁さんになります！
With this, Rushia will become everyone's bride!
可愛いでしょう！
It's cute, right?
もうお部屋とかね、パソコンデスクの周りとか、君の近くに、すぐそばに置いておいてください！
Please keep it close to you, like in your room or around your computer desk, right by your side!
るしあがずっと見てるからね！
Rushia will be watching you all the time!
そして2点目は、るしあと一生一緒エンゲージリングです！
And the second item is the "Together Forever with Rushia Engagement Ring"!
これは、これは、結婚指輪というやつではないですかー？
Isn't this... isn't this what you'd call a wedding ring?!
どうですか？
What do you think?
これは、君たちと一緒に付ける指輪です！
This is a ring to wear together with all of you!
いや、ちょっとドキドキしちゃうね！
Wow, my heart is beating so fast!
とっても綺麗で可愛くない？
Isn't it super pretty and cute?
もう、生涯に一度の代物ですよ！
It's truly a once-in-a-lifetime item!
素敵でしょう！
It's wonderful, right?
いや、これはみんなと一緒に是非是非是非つけたい！
Man, I really, really, REALLY want to wear this with everyone!
るしあ毎日これを付けて配信します！
Rushia will wear this every single day during streams!
そして、最後の3点目はこちら！
And here is the third and final item!
魚先生描き下ろしのペアマグカップセットになります！
It's a pair mug cup set with new illustrations by Sakana-sensei!
いやぁ、ペアだらけだね！ペアだらけだね！
Man, it's full of matching items! Matching items everywhere!
見て、このマグカップ！
Look at these mug cups!
朝起きた時とか、寝る前とか休憩とか、もうずっと一緒なんだよ！
When you wake up in the morning, before bed, during breaks... we'll be together all the time!
可愛いでしょう！
Isn't it cute?
これはね、るしあバージョンとふぁんでっとちゃんバージョンのコップになります！
These are cups featuring the Rushia version and the Fandead-chan version!
いや、みんなと使いたいな！
I really want to use them with everyone!
君とおそろいいっぱいになったね！
Now we have so many matching items together!
これもね、配信しながらるしあ使って飲んでいるから、
Rushia will be drinking from this while streaming too, so...
君たちもるしあの配信見ながらこれを使って飲めば、もうるしまたち結婚生活だね！
if you drink from it while watching Rushia's stream, it's basically like we're living married life together!
はい！こんなにね、素敵なグッズたくさん盛りだくさん、どうですか？
Yep! There are so many wonderful items packed in here, what do you think?
そしてなんと、なんと、なんと！誕生日記念フルセットには、今紹介したグッズにるしあの複製サイン入りポストカードがついてきます！
And what's more, what's more, what's more! The Birthday Celebration Full Set comes with a postcard featuring Rushia's printed signature along with the items introduced!
で、で、で！数量限定バージョンのものには、るしあの直筆メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます！
And, and, and! The limited quantity version comes with a postcard featuring Rushia's hand-written message!
直筆ですよ、直筆！要チェックですよ！要チェック！
It's hand-written! Hand-written! Be sure to check it out! Check it out!
周年記念のサインも書き終わっているので、
I've already finished signing the anniversary ones as well,
改めてみんなのために愛情深く深く込めたメッセージを書いていきます！
so I'll be writing messages filled with deep, deep affection for everyone once again!
よかったらみんな、どんどん感想ツイートなどなどしていってね！
Feel free to tweet your thoughts and impressions, okay?
そしてまだ、実はここだけ終わりではなくて、もう少し見てもらいたいものがあります！
And actually, it doesn't end here! There's something else I'd like you to see!
いきます！
Here we go!
ジャジャン！
Ta-da!
みんなー！
Everyone~!
今日は本当に本当に生誕祭ライブ...
Thank you all so so much for today's Birthday Concert Live...
見に来てくれて本当にありがとうね
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
何か気づいたことある？
Did you notice anything?
この猫耳ついているでしょうかー？
Do you see these cat ears?
じゃんじゃーん！
Ta-da!
こちらは実はるしあのお誕生日だからと言って
Actually, since it's Rushia's birthday,
やすゆきお父様がるしあにプレゼントしてくださいました！
Yasuyuki-papa gave them to me as a gift!
可愛いね～！似合ってるね～！
So cute! They suit me, right?
ということでこの姿でも配信をしていくので
So I'll be streaming in this form too,
みんなこれからも仲良く、仲良く、るしあと遊んでいってください！
so please keep having fun and hanging out with Rushia!
そしてグッズなんですけど 10時から販売されるので
Also, regarding the merch, sales start from 10:00,
概要欄から飛んで行って どんどんグッズをお手にとってみてください！
so click the link in the description and check out the merch!
サイン要チェックですよ！
Be sure to check out the signed items!
他にもね 素敵な指輪など マグカップなどたくさんあるので
There are also lots of other cool items like rings and mugs,
みんな 良かったらたくさんそばに置いてみてください！
so please keep them by your side if you like!
本当に本当に今日は素敵な1日をありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for such a wonderful day today!
みんな大好きだよ！本当にありがとう！
I love you all! Thank you so much!
みんな、せーの、おつるしー！
Everyone, ready... Otsurushi~!
ありがとう！
Thank you!